Guide to the John R. Blaney papers, 1953-2001 and undated RL.11598
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Print Material, 1953-2000; undated; 4
  - Prevention Magazine--Study on OTC/DTC medicines, 1997 (Box 28)
  - Primary Contact--Creativity: What Works?, undated (Box 28)
  - Primary Contact--How Research Can Help in the Creation of Effective Advertising, undated (Box 28)
  - Primary Contact--How to Evaluate Advertising, undated (Box 28)
  - Primary Contact--How to Handle International Advertising, undated (Box 28)
  - Primary Contact--The Importance of Branding, undated (Box 28)
  - Primary Contact--The Most Neglected Marketing Target: The Staff, undated (Box 28)
  - Promotional Campaigns, Ltd.--Ideas that Sell, 1990 (Box 28)
  - Research International--The Body and Its Environment, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Ruder Finn--Communications brochures, undated (Box 28)
  - Ruder Finn--Financial Management, 1998 (Box 29)
  - Sir Michael Perry--The Brand: Vehicle for Value in a Changing Market Place, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Sound As Good As You Look, undated (Box 29)
  - Special Counsel International brochure, 1991 (Box 29)
  - T. Laco--If I Were a Brand Manager Today, 1981 (Box 29)
  - Telecard World, 1995 (Box 29)
  - The Lasker Story, 1953 (Box 29)
  - Tom Dillon (BBDO)--AAF Hall of Fame speech, 1978 (Box 29)
  - Tony Houghton--Speech on trends, undated (Box 29)
  - Wall Street Journal--7 Steps to Improving Your Corporate Image, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Wall Street Journal--How Corporate Branding Contributes to Marketing and Financial Suddess, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Wall Street Journal--Maximizing Your Corporate Brand, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Wall Street Journal--Why Advertise?, 1991 (Box 29)
  - William Bernbach--Facts Are Not Enough, 1980 (Box 29)
  - William Esty--Setting Creative Strategy, 1978 (Box 29)
  - You Can Be a Branding Hero!, 2000 (Box 29)
- Writings and Speeches, 1972-1999; undated; 5
  - Borders Are Not Barriers, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Borders Without Barriers, undated (Box 29)
  - Brand Positioning and Personality, undated (Box 29)
  - Brand Stewardship and Unilever, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Branding and Advertising Strategy, 1987 (Box 29)
  - Branding for the 90s and Beyond, 1991 (Box 29)
  - Branding videotape talk, undated (Box 29)
  - Direct to Consumer Advertising, 1999 (Box 29)
  - European Management Meeting, 1991 (Box 29)
  - How to Manage International Advertising, 1991 (Box 29)
  - Idea file and drafts, 1989-1995 (Box 30)
  - International Advertising, 1990 (Box 30)
  - International Advertising presentation, undated (Box 30)
  - Management of Worldwide Accounts, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - New Product Individuality, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Pond's Brand and Pond's Institute, undated (Box 30)
  - Prescription Drug Advertising to the Consumer, 1984 (Box 30)
  - Presentation notes and miscellaneous, 1989; undated (Box 30)
  - Pros and Cons of Assigning One Brand, Product or Service to One Worldwide Advertising Agency, undated (Box 30)
  - Role of Advertising in Marketing, 1980 (Box 30)
  - Rotary Club Luncheon talk, 1985 (Box 30)
  - Speech file--Correspondence, 1984 (Box 30)
  - Talk to Account Management Training Program, 1984 (Box 30)
  - The Chemistry Was Right, 1984 (Box 30)
  - The Shock of the New, 1988 (Box 30)
  - Unilever: What We've Learned, 1987 (Box 30)
  - Unilever and Ogilvy & Mather, 1994 (Box 30)
  - Unilever Europe/North America Conference (Kinsale), 1989 (Box 30)
  - Unilever Latin America Conference, 1988 (Box 30)
  - What Every Account Manager Should Know About International Advertising (draft for AAAA booklet), 1996 (Box 30)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Expects from You in Client Service, undated (Box 30)
  - Why We Need Mozarts on International Business, undated (Box 30)
  - Worldwide Management Meeting, 1989 (Box 30)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1984-1995; undated; 6
  - A. Eicoff & Company compilation, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-001)
  - Apple Mackintosh "1984" :60 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-002)
  - Bob Newhart "Vision Development", 1993 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-003)
    Scope and Contents
    School for Bus Drivers; King Kong; The Driving Instructor; Abe Lincoln Versus Madison Avenue; Cruise of the USS Codfish; Defusing the Bomb; Nude Line Up; Introducing Tobacco to Civilization; The Retirement Party
  - BTA Awards reel, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-004)
  - Category Management Interview, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-005)
    Harry Groome and Louise Sibley. Aquafresh commercials from 6 countries
  - Chesebrough Pond's International, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-006)
    The Story Behind the Doors; Executional Guidelines for Television
  - Chesebrough Pond's Worldwide Reel, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-007)
  - David Ogilvy Magic Lanterns, 1991 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-008)
  - Dove and Pond's International Reel, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-009)
    Dove: Jean Shy (US); Viviana Sehweret (US Hispanic); Veronique Marty (France); Raffaela Davi (Italy); Joanne Chong (Singapore). Pond's: Age-Defying Complex, Prevent and Correct (US); Cleansing Milk and Toner (UK); Skin Lightening Cream (Thailand); Crema C (Mexico); Vanishing Cream (Nairobi)
  - Dove Bar: Selection of commercials for John Blaney, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-010)
  - Duracell International Advertising, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-011)
  - Global Advertising Presentation--John Blaney, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-012)
  - Global Advertising Presentation--John Blaney, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-013)
  - Global Advertising Presentation--John Blaney, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-014)
  - HBA/PacRim Symposium, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-015)
  - Healthcare Magic Lantern, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-016)
  - IAA Presentation Video 12:08, Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-017)
  - IBM Brand 9 spots, 1995 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-018)
  - John Blaney Compilation Reel 12:10, 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-019)
  - Le Sancy Toilet Soap spots (O&M India), 1995 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-020)
  - Miscellaneous (24 commercials), Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-021)
  - Museum of Broadcasting Part 1 of 2 (67 commercials), 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-022)
  - Museum of Broadcasting Part 2 of 2 (39 commercials), 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-023)
  - Nationwide Insurance "Dreams", Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-024)
  - New Product Magic Lantern (30 commercials), 1990 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-025)
  - Ogilvy & Mather show reel, 1995 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-026)
    Commercials from Microsoft, Kraft, AT&T
  - Ogilvy compilation, 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-027)
    Paradiso (Germany); Mirage (France); other commercials
  - Procter & Gamble: Re-Engineering the Global Dragon, 1994 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-028)
  - Richard Fowler: The Big Idea, 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-029)
  - Ross Sutherland Shell Presentation, 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-030)
  - Superbowl XXVII commercials taken off the air, 1994 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-031)
  - TV Commercials 1950s-1970s (25 commercials), Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-032)
  - Unilever Creative Conference (Norman Berry, Richard Fowler), 1988 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-033)
  - Unilever WMS compilation of Hamlet commercials, 1991 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-034)
  - View from Toufou 45:00, Undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-035)
  - Vita Mix "Mother, Mother, Mother", Undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-036)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Expects from You in Client Service 18:00, 1992 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-037)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Expects from You in Client Service 18:00, Undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-Umatic-038)
  - Channel 5: Count Basie and Friends 1943-1945, Undated (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11598-VHS-001)
  - Global Advertising Presentation--John Blaney, Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-VHS-002)
  - Pharmaceuticals montage, Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11598-VHS-003)
  - IAA Board Meeting/VP mailing, 1995 (Box AV1, Disk 1)
    3.5 disk, IBM format. Contents: Board Meeting minutes Zurich June 1995; Executive Committee meeting minutes; Treasurer's Report 1994-1995; Fiscal Report 1994-1995; Chapter Development Summary; Corporate Development Summary; Action Plan 1995-1996